

# Serhii Mykhailov

**DevOps Engineer** 

mykhailovsa@gmail.com

linkedin.com/in/s-mykhailov t.me/mykhailov s github.com/Mihailov-SA mynote.pp.ua fb.com/mykhailov.s/

#### About me:

Risen from SysAdmin to DevOps.

10+ years of experience as a System Administrator with a huge background in server infrastructure and datacenter operations management, strong knowledge of Windows/Linux, and networking.

3+ years as a DevOps Engineer with experience in Infrastructure as Code (IaC), Configuration as Code (CaC), CI/CD, and proficiency in almost all AWS cloud features.

Results and customer-oriented. Skilled in communication, problem localization and solving, critical thinking, and openmindedness. Self-motivated and self-managing, with a strong ability for self-education. Extremely composed, methodical, and cold-blooded when handling critical issues.

My motto: Anything that needs to be repeated more than twice should be automated.

my work == my hobby.

## **Experience:**

#### Automat-IT (DevOps company)

Role: DevOps Engineer, Jan 2021 - present

As a DevOps Engineer at Automat-IT, I play an important role in optimizing and streamlining the software development and deployment processes for multiple end customers with various stacks and configurations. Leveraging my expertise in infrastructure automation, CI/CD, and system administration background, I have contributed to enhancing the overall software development lifecycle, infrastructure scalability, fault tolerance, reliability, and scalable software delivery.

#### **Kev Achievements:**

- Several migrations from on-prem/Azure MySQL/MSSQL to AWS RDS databases via AWS DMS and 3rd party services
- Developing a Terraform module for the AWS managed OpenSearch service
- Experience with migration of large amounts of data from on-prem VM's to hundreds S3 buckets with continuous replication as part of migration on-prem FTP services to AWS.
- Set up and support both new and existing infrastructure in the cloud across all major cloud providers, with a primary focus on AWS.

### **Technologies and Tools:**

IaC: Terraform, Pulumi, CloudFormation.

CI/CD: Jenkins, GitHub Actions, AWS CodePipeline | CodeBuild.

CaC: Ansible, AWS SSM.

Scripting: Bash, Python, Groovy, SQL.

Monitoring: Cloudwatch, NewRelic, Zabbix, Grafana, Datadog, OpenSearch.

Knowledge of all major AWS tools and services, including EC2, Lambda, ECS, S3, EBS, RDS, ELB, Route53, CloudFront, CloudWatch, and more. Experience with hybrid environments (VMware ESXi + AWS).

#### LIDER-TREYD LTD (logistics)

Role: System Administrator, 2015 - 2021

Setup and support hypervisors based on Hyper-V; Citrix XEN;

Windows 2008-2016: AD; GPO; DNS; DHCP; IIS; RDP/remote-app; MSSQL; 1C 7-8.2; SEP controller;

Debian based: mysql; apache; owncloud; samba; pbisopen; vsftpd; jabber; motion; docker; zabbix; traccar.

Networking: Mikrotik; Zywall; Draytek; Ubiquiti, HP procurve. Firewall; DHCP; DNS; NAT; openvpn; IPsec; site-to-site VPN; Load-Balancing; WiFi-roaming;

Support users workstations based on Windows XP-10. Selection of components and assembly of bare metal servers. Configuration backups, replications (master-slave), helpdesk services and monitoring. Bash; powershell; python; RouterOS scripting. Cloud providers: DigitalOcean.

#### Epicall (call centre)

XenServer v6.5 hypervisor. CentOS based VMs. Configuring tunnels for customers servers. Support users workstations based on Ubuntu. Setting up the company's internal LAN and WiFi.

## **DVBTD** (brokerage company)

Role: System Administrator, 2010 - 2014

Debian-based server: LAMP; SAMBA; FTP; OpenVPN; CUPS. Support workstations based on Windows XP-7. Configuring and support company's website, LAN, WiFi.

## **Education and certification details:**

## Udemy | AWS SysOps Administrator

2022. AWS SOA-C02 Exam

Certification was successful.

Cert Validation Number: ZXL4JNGCTBB1QH9V.

# **Udemy | AWS Cloud Practitioner**

2021, AWS CLF-C01 exam

Certification was successful.

Cert Validation Number: JV2Z3P2DD1411QS0.

#### **DevOps course Zone3000**

2020, DevOps Basics

Successfully completed the course and received a  $\,\underline{\text{certificate}}.$ 

#### **Donetsk National University of Economics and Trade**

2010 - 2014, Master

Mechanical engineering

#### **Skills summary:**

## Operating Systems | Hypervisors | Container runtimes:

Linux: Debian, Alpine, Ubuntu, CenOS, Amazon Linux.

Windows: 7-10, Server 2003-2019

Hyper-V, Proxmox, VMware ESXi, XEN, LXC, Docker

### IAAC I CAAC:

Terraform, Pulumi, CloudFormation, Ansible, AWS SSM

## CI/CD tools:

Jenkins, CodeBuild/CodePipeline, GitHub Actions

### Scripting:

Bash, Python, PowerShell, Groovy, SQL

## DB Engines (administration level):

MySQL, MSSQL, RDS Aurora

### Hardware:

Mikrotik, Ubiquiti, Zyxel Zywall, Draytek, HP ProCurve, HP proliant, Supermicro. Experience in selecting components and assembling bare-metal servers

## Language:

English - Intermediate Ukrainian - Native Russian - Native

Last updated at 14/08/2024 by GitHub Actions